Guide to the Works Progress Administration oral histories collection, 1961-1984
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Works Progress Administration oral histories collection
1961-1984
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
George Mason University. Institute on the Federal Theatre Project and New Deal Culture
C0153
7 linear feet (11 boxes)
This compilation describes oral interviews with persons who were associated with various Works Progress Administration (WPA) projects in the 1930s. These include the Federal Art Project, Federal Music Project, and Federal Writers Project.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by the Institute on the Federal Theatre Project and New Deal Culture.
Historical Information
The interviews in the WPA Oral Histories Collection were conducted from between 1961 and 1984. The majority of the interviews were done in the 1970s and 1980s by Lorraine Brown and John O'Connor as part of the Institute on the Federal Theatre Project and New Deal Culture.
Scope and Content
This compilation describes oral interviews with persons who were associated with various Works Progress Administration (WPA) projects in the 1930s. These include the Federal Art Project, Federal Music Project, and Federal Writers Project.
The interviews (transcripts and tapes) are arranged in alphabetical order by the subject's last name. The date of the interview is included along with the type of work or position held by the interviewee during the 1930s, with the location when known. The name of the interviewer(s) follows. In some cases a notation is made indicating that an interview is untaped. If the interview was a joint one, this information is noted. The type of media available (abstract, letter, notes, tape, and/or transcript)is then listed along with the number of pages or minutes of each type. Restrictions that may apply to certain interviews is the last information in an entry.
List of Abbreviations:
CCC - Civilian Conservation Corps, FAP - Federal Art Project, FERA - Federal Emergency Relief Administration, FMP - Federal Music Project, FTP - Federal Theatre Project, FWP - Federal Writers Project, GSA - General Services Administration, NYA - National Youth Administration, SECT - Section of Painting and Sculpture, WPA - Works Projects Adminstration
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by last name of interviewee.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Federal Art Project.; Federal Music Project (U.S.); Federal Theatre Project (U.S.); United States. Works Progress Administration.
Subjects:
Acting.; Dance--United States.; New Deal, 1933-1939.; Theater--United States.
Contents List
- Work Projects Administration Oral Histories
  - Allison, Elitea, November 10,1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Widow of playwright Hughes Allison, whose work was produced by FTP.
  - Anderson, Thomas, May 24, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Stage manager and director with the Negro unit, NYC FTP.
  - Andrus, Zoray, February 24, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Costume designer with SF FTP.
  - Archer, Osceola, January 3, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Actress who auditioned for Negro Unit, NYC FTP.
  - Bacon, Ernst, April 23, 1982 (Box 1)
    Composer and director, SF FMP.
  - Baird, Bill, November 8, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Technician, marionette artist, and actor with the Classical unit, NYC FTP.
  - Bales, Richard Corner, June 2, 1982 (Box 1)
    Conductor, FMP's Virginia Symphony Orchestra and North Carolina-Virginia Symphony.
  - Bales, William, May 23, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Dancer and assistant to Charles Weidman, with NYC Federal Dance Theatre.
  - Banfield, Beryl, May 22, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Dancer with the Negro unit, NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Barber, Philip, January 11, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Administrative director of the NYC FTP.
  - Barber, Philip, February 20, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Barlin, Anne Lief, October 25, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Dancer with Federal Dance Project, NYC.
  - Barnouw, Eric, May 12,1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Worked with the Radio Division of FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Baron, Paul, December 5, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Stage manager with the Manhattan City Projects, NYC.
  - Bates, Add, November 30, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Dancer and actor with NYC FTP units.
  - Bay, Howard, February 21, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Set designer for various NYC FTP productions.
  - Bentley, Eric, May 12, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Son-in-law of Hallie Flanagan; writer and critic of modern drama.
  - Bentley, Joanne Davis, May 13, 1976 (Box 1)
    Step-daughter of Hallie Flanagan. Closed pending release.
  - Benton, Thomas Hart, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Artist, muralist. Unidentified interviewer may have residual rights to interview.
  - Berenberg, Ben, August 16,1977 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Actor with Children's Theatre and Living Newspaper units of NYC FTP.
  - Berman, Harold, November 16,1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Writer who worked with the National Play Bureau, NYC FTP. Restricted during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Novelist, film writer, journalist, NYC, LA. Approval of Sylviane Bessie required.
  - Birchenall, Jack, November 18, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Black, Ivan, May 8, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Administrator with NYC FTP Radio Division; also worked as publicist with NYC FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Blake, Eubie, January 9, 1977 (Box 1)
    Composer, musician; wrote Swing It for NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Blankfort, Michael, July 22, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Playwright whose play, Battle Hymn, written with Michael Gold, was produced by various FTP units.
  - Bolotowski, Ilya, January 30, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Artist, muralist with NYC FAP. Permission for publication required.
  - Bolton, Harold (Box 1, Folder 23)
    [see Bolton, Philip.]
  - Bolton, Philip, April 7, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Son of Harold (director and choreographer with NYC FTP) and Rhoda Rammelkamp Bolton (costume designer, NYC FTP). This is an untaped interview.
  - Bolton, Rhoda Rammelkamp (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Borowski, Maxine, June 2, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Costume designer with NYC FTP.
  - Bosworth, Francis, September 29, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Director of Play Bureau; in charge of exhibits; head of Play Reading Bureau within the National Office of FTP.
  - Brant, Carl, March 16, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Actor with LA FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Breen, Robert, November 27, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Director and actor with Chicago FTP.
  - Breen, Wilva Davis, November 27, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Director and actress with Chicago FTP.
  - Brocco, Peter, June 1, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Actor with LA FTP.
  - Bromley, Robert, June 30, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Director of marionette unit of LA FTP.
  - Brook, Alexander, January 2, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Artist with FAP. Permission for publication required.
  - Browne, Theodore, October 22, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Playwright whose work was produced by Seattle FTP; also a writer with Boston FTP.
  - Bruskin, Perry, 10-22-76 October 22, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Actor with Children's unit of NYC FTP.
  - Burris-Meyer, Harold, March 14, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Sound technician with Living Newspaper unit of NYC FTP.
  - Buttitta, Tony, January 11, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Publicist with NYC FTP.
  - Cadmus, Paul, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Artist, muralist with FAP. Closed pending release.
  - Cameniti, Ida, March 15, 1977 (Box 2)
    Playwright whose work, Reward, was produced by the Tampa FTP. Closed during Fernando Mesa's lifetime.
  - Campbell, Dick, November 10, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Director of Lafayette Theatre's Negro unit of NYC FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Cardwell, Laurence, March 17, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Personnel administrator with NYC and Florida FTP units.
  - Carter, Clarence Holbrook, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Artist, administrator with Ohio FAP. Permission with interviewer required for publication.
  - Catlett, Elizabeth, Decenber 8, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Artist, NY. Permission to quote over 100 words required.
  - Chaivoe, Nick, January 18, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Actor, stage manager with Portland, OR FTP. Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Chase, Mary Coyle, August 9, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Playwright whose work was produced by Denver FTP.
  - Chavkin, Samuel, May 22,1978 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Publicist with Federal Dance Theatre, NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Cheney, Sheldon, December 29,1975 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Writer and theater critic. Closed pending release.
  - Chesse, Ralph, 1974 (Box 2)
    Director of marionette units, SF and LA FTP; costume designer.
  - Chesse, Ralph, June 23, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Chilkovsky, Nadia May 25, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    Choreographer and dancer with Federal Dance Project, NYC FTP.
  - Cikovsky, Nicolai, 7-18-80July 18, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Artist with the Illinois and District of Columbia FAP. Permission of interviewer required for publication.
  - Cisney, Marcella (Box 3)
    See Schnitzer, Marcella Cisney.
  - Clark, Helen Fisher, August 7, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    With Children's Theatre unit, NYC FTP.
  - Clark, Maurice, August 7, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Theatrical director with Experimental and Children's units, NYC FTP.
  - Clarke, David, July 21, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Assistant stage manager with Classical unit, NYC FTP.
  - Clebanoff, Herman, April 21, 1982 (Box 3)
    Concertmaster, Illinois Symphony Orchestra.
  - Clugston, Katherine T., December 28, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Director of Play Bureau, NYC FTP.
  - Clugston, Katherine T. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Director of Play Bureau, NYC FTP. Closed until completion of dissertation.
  - Cohen, Elizabeth Elson, January 14, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    District supervisor with SF FTP.
  - Cohn, Arthur, May 6, 1982 (Box 3)
    Supervisor of Copyists unit of Philadelphia FMP; conductor of Philadelphia Orchestra.
  - Coleman, Ralf, November 24, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Director of Negro unit, Boston FTP. Permission to quote required.
  - Coleman, Ralf, November 21, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Director of Negro unit, Boston FTP.
  - Connelly, Marc, October 23, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Playwright whose works were produced by various FTP units.
  - Corey, Jeff, October 24, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Actor with NYC FTP.
  - Cotten, Joseph, February 22, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Actor with Classical unit,NYC FTP.
  - Courlander, Harold, August 10, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    Playwright whose work, Swamp Mud, was produced in Birmingham, AL.
  - Cox, Margaret, February 5, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    WPA administrative assistant and secretary, Washington, D.C. and NY. Closed pending release.
  - Cronbach, Robert, February 26, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Sculptor with FAP. Permission of interviewer required for publication.
  - Cronin, Anne, October 29, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    Administrative assistant to Ellen Woodward, WPA's head of Woman's and Professional Division, Washington, D.C. FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Croydon, Joan, December 16, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    Actress with Roslyn, NY unit of FTP.
  - Cunningham, Michele Elliott, May 28, 1976 (Box 3)
    Actress, dancer, playwright, and marionette manipulator with SF FTP.
  - Da Silva, Howard, May 24, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Actor and director with Radio Division, NYC FTP.
  - Daggett, Helen Cross, April 18, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Worked with various productions of FTP in California. Permission of interviewer required for publication.
  - Daly, Frank, June 11, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    Actor with the Roslyn, NY FTP unit.
  - Danzig, Frank, July 19, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    Writer with Radio Division, NYC FTP.
  - Davidson, Julius, December 14, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    Finance administrator, WPA arts projects, Washington, D.C.
  - De Koven, Roger, January 8, 1980 (Box 3)
    Actor with Popular Price Theatre, NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - De Paur, Leonard December 2, 1976, December 28,1976, January 11, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    Music director with the Negro unit, NYC FTP.
  - Dehn, Mura, April 20, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    Dancer and choreographer with the dance unit, NYC FTP.
  - Del Bourgo, Fanya Geltman, December 16, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    Dancer with the dance unit, NYC FTP.
  - Denby, Edwin, March 2, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Play adapter and choreographer with Classical unit, NYC FTP.
  - Dowell, George B., April 30, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Assistant to Hallie Flanagan at Smith College; playwright.
  - Du Bois, Shirley Graham, May 28, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Playwright with Chicago FTP. Permission to quote over 100 words required.
  - Dudley Jr., Edward, October 27, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Assistant stage manager with Negro unit, NYC FTP.
  - Durham, C.J.S. (Jack), June 23, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Worked in Herbert Hoover's and Harry Hopkins's press offices.
  - Ebsen, Nancy Wolcott, June 1, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Student of Hallie Flanagan; expert in children's theater.
  - Edson, Eda, May 30, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Director of Vaudeville unit, Los Angeles, FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Edwards, Ben, December 28, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Set designer with the Roslyn, NY unit of the FTP.
  - Eldridge, Elaine, November 27, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Actress with the Children's Theatre, NYC FTP.
  - Elson, Charles, December 1, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Set designer with the Los Angeles FTP.
  - Elson, Diane Rivers, December 1, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Actress with the Los Angeles FTP.
  - Engel, Lehman, October 23, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Musical composer and director with various units, NYC FMP and FTP.
  - Engel, Lehman, May 8, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Ewing, Kay, November 27, 1979 (Box 4)
    Director of Negro unit and Children's unit, Chicago, FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Farmer, Virginia, August 11, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Director of Southwest Experimental unit, Los Angeles FTP.
  - Farnsworth, William, March 16, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Administrative assistant to Hallie Flanagan, national office, FTP.
  - Farran, Don, January 3, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Director, Midwest FTP; administrator for Federal Arts Projects in Chicago and Washington, D.C.
  - Feder, Abe, May 13, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Lighting designer with the Negro and Classical units, NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Ferguson, Kenneth, September 19, 1975 (Box 4)
    Brother of Hallie Flanagan. This is an untaped interview.
  - Fishel, H.L. (Bud), October 26, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    Administrator with the National Play Bureau; playwright, play reader, NYC FTP.
  - Fisher, Granville, March 19,1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Director of Miami unit, FTP.
  - Forbes, Leon, July 19, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    Actor with SF FTP
  - Francis, Arlene, April 17, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    Actress with the Classical unit, NYC FTP
  - Frank, Allan, October 25, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    Actor with Children's Theatre, NYC FTP
  - Frankel, Lillian Berson, October 10, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    Writer with Radio Division, Illinois Writers' Project
  - Freeman, Charles K., February 20, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    Producer and Theatrical Director, NYC FTP
  - Freud, Mayfair, January 5, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Wife of Ralph Freud, theatrical director and actor with LA FTP
  - Freud, Mayfair, January 8, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Wife of Ralph Freud, theatrical director and actor with LA FTP.
  - Freud, Ralph, November 1, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Theatrical director and actor with LA and SF FTP.
  - Friar, Kimon, May 1976 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Playwright and technical assistant with the Detroit FTP.
  - Galea, Manuel see Myra Kinch February 21. 1976 (Box 5)
    Composer; accompanist with Dance Project, LA FTP.
  - Garnet, Eva Desca, October 26, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Dancer and assistant to Doris Humphrey with the Dance Project, NYC FTP.
  - Geer, Will, June 1, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Actor, NYC FTP.
  - Gellert, Lawrence, October 22, 1976 (Box 5)
    Writer and Publicist with FWP and the Negro unit, NYC FTP; play reader with FTP Play Bureau. Closed pending release.
  - Gerrard, Saida, February 21, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Dancer with the Dance Project, NYC FTP
  - Gilbert, Lou, April 16, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Actor and founder of Chicago Repertory Group, 1933.
  - Gilder, Rosamond, November 16, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Administrator, Bureau of research and Publications of FTP.
  - Gilder, Rosamond, February 19, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Administrator, Bureau of Research and Publications of FTP.
  - Gilman, Harold, November 30, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Actor with the Chicago FTP.
  - Gilman, Ida Galler, November 30, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Dancer with the Chicago FTP.
  - Glidden, Patty Neederman, July 23, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Actress and dancer with the Vaudeville unit, LA FTP
  - Glyer, Richard, July 19, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Actor with the LA FTP; director with the Seattle FTP.
  - Goldberg, Albert, April 19, 1982 (Box 5)
    State director of the Illinois FMP.
  - Goodman, Frank, June 9, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Publicist with NYC FTP; director, Department of Information, FTP.
  - Gorelik, Mordecai, January 3, 1976 (Box 5)
    Designer, theater historian; critic.
  - Graham, Hedley Gordon, February 27, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    Theatrical director with the Atlanta, Tampa, and Chicago units of the FTP.
  - Graham, Hedley Gordon, May 27, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Green, Paul, December 1, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    Playwright, some of whose works were produced by various FTP units.
  - Hairston, Jester, December 27, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    Musical director with the LA and SF FTP. Permission to quote more than 100 words required.
  - Hairston, Jester, May 29, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    Musical director with the LA and SF FTP.Closed until 1996; or permission of interviewee.
  - Harris, Julian H. (Box 5, Folder 17)
    Art director with the Atlanta FTP.
  - Haufrecht, Herbert, July 18, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Staff composer and arranger with FTP.
  - Hauser, Ethel Aaron, February 20, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Stage manager and publicity director with the Living Newspaper unit, NYC FTP.
  - Hays, Hoffman R., June 8, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Writer and researcher with the Living Newspaper unit, NYC FTP.
  - Hill, Abram, February 27, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    Play reader and playwright with the NYC FTP. Permission required for commercial use.
  - Hill, Abram, March 30, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    Play reader and playwright with the NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Horn, Axel, January 3, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    Muralist with the FAP and SECT in NY and Ohio. Permission of interviewer required for publication.
  - Houghton, Norris, May 13, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Writer, critic, producer, designer with the NY theaters i the 1930s.
  - Houseman, John, May 11, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Producer and administrator with the Negro and Classical units, NYC FTP.
  - Hurwitz, Leo, September 27, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Participated in the Resettlement Administration.
  - Isaacs, Lewis, November 9, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Son of Edith Isaacs, editor of Theatre Arts Magazine; friend of FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Izenour, George, February 1976 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    Lighting designer with the LA FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Johnson, Lamont, May 28, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Theatrical director familiar with the LA and NYC FTP.
  - Jonas, Hallie, May 29, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Publicist and promotion officer with the NYC FTP.
  - Kayes, Alan, May 11, 1982 (Box 6)
    Director of information with the NYC FMP.
  - Kennedy, Donald Scott, September 1976 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Actor with the SF FTP.
  - Kent, Charlotte, December 15, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    Songwriter and composer with the NYC FTP.
  - Kinch, Myra, February 21,1976 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Choreographer and dancer with the Dance Project, LA FTP.
  - Kingston, Lenore, October 24,1977 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Actress with the San Bernardino/Riverside and LA FTP.
  - Kinnard, Henry, January 3, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Stagehand with the NYC FTP.Closed pending release.
  - Koch, Howard, October 26, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Playwright with the NYC FTP.
  - Kondolf, George, February 21, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Administrative director, Chicago and NYC FTP.
  - Krakow, Leo, April 30, 1982 (Box 6)
    Concertmaster of the Grand Rapids, MI FTP orchestra.
  - Lane, Esther Porter, September 7, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Stage manager, administrator, theatrical director with the FTP in NYC, Washington, D.C., and Seattle, WA.
  - Lane, Esther Porter, July 11, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Lantz, Louis, May 26, 1976 (Box 6)
    Playwright whose works were produced by the NYC FTP. Closed pending release.
  - Larsen, Agnete Johansen, November 18,1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Actress with the SF and Oakland FTP. This is an untaped interview.
  - Laub, Lili Mann, May 24, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Dancer with the Dance Project, NYC FTP.
  - Laurence, Paula, April 20, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Actress with the Classical unit, NYC FTP.
  - Lavery, Emmet, January 5, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Administrator with the National Service Bureau of the FTP.
  - Lavery, Emmet, October 17,1977 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    Director, National Service Bureau of the FTP.
  - Lawson, Kathryn Drain, January 3, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Director of Bureau of Research and Publication, NYC FTP.Bound with the 1-4-76 transcript.
  - Lawson, Kathryn Drain, January 4, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Director of Bureau of Research and Publication, NYC FTP.Bound with the 1-3-76 transcript.
  - Le Noire, Rosetta, January 8, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Actress with the Negro unit, NYC FTP. Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Leavitt, Max, November 28, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Puppeteer with the Marionette Project, NYC FTP.Closed during lifetime.
  - Lee, J. Edward, July 20, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Publicist with NYC and Chicago FTP. Interview not to be used for gain or profit without the consent of the interviewee.
  - Lee, Will, September 22, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Actor with the several units of the NYC FTP.
  - Lehac, Ned May/June 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Lyricist whose work was featured in the NYC FTP production of Sing For Your Supper.
  - Lentz, Josef, April 7, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Administrator with the New Orleans and Atlanta FTP.Permission for use required during Mr. Lentz's lifetime.
  - Lessin, Harry, January 6, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Leve, Samuel, February 21, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Set designer with NYC FTP.
  - Levin, Meyer, January 4, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Playwright whose Model Tenements was produced by the Chicago FTP.
  - Lewitsky, Bella, March 12, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Dancer with the Dance Project, LA FTP.
  - Lief, Arthur, June 7, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Teacher and conductor with NYC FMP. Closed during interviewee's lifetime.
  - Lindemulder, Nel, October 28, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Interviewee's husband, Gerhardt Lindemulder, was a director with the FTP in Louisiana and Florida.
  - Lipe, Howard, December 5, 1976 (Box 7)
    Vaudeville performer with the FTP.
  - Litvinoff, Valentina, November 29, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Dancer with the Children's unit and Dance Project, NYC FTP.Tape restricted.
  - Lloyd, Joel, November 14, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 10)